

Address: 74 Joslyn Crescent, ParsonVlei, Port Elizaeth, 6025

Phone: 0618180752

Email: shadrackdrack@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/sdracksith

Summary

Experienced Software, and Network Engineer with over 5 years of experience in Information Technology industry. Excellent reputation for resolving problems and improving customer satisfaction. Assist in configuration of company applications based on business requirements document and obtain approval from business owners. Plan and execute assigned configuration tasks within deadlines and assist in system analysis, design, development, and testing activities. Performs IT functions such as design, analysis, evaluation, testing, debugging and implementation of applications programs supporting the company infrastructure business processes and operations and/or network-based (cloud) product systems. Analyses, installs, acquires, modifies and supports operating systems, database or utilities software. Plans, conducts and directs the analysis of business problems with automated systems solutions.

Skill Highlights

Microsoft Word, Excel, Access Database operation: Microsoft Office Access, MySQL, PostgreSQL Programming: C#,HTML, CSS, Javascript, Ruby Troubleshooting skills Network configuration and support Computer Security Cloud Support Network Security Server Support Application monitoring AWS CLI, Virtualization and Docker

Experience

09/2021 - Current

Senior Technical Support Engineer – PartnerHero

Responsibilities:

- Monitors customer solutions and solve customer reported issues through zendesk ticketing system
- Test and troubleshoot API using Postman

04/2020 - 2022

MS Engineer L1 – NOC at Dimension Data, Port Elizabeth in South Africa

Responsibilities:

- Monitors client infrastructure and solutions
- Identify problems and errors prior to or when they occur
- Routinely identify common incidents and opportunities for avoidance as well as general opportunities for incident reduction
- Investigate first line incidents assigned and identify the root cause of incidents and problems
- Fulfil approved requests following agreed procedures
- Provide telephonic or chat support to clients when required
- Execute approved maintenance activities including patching and configuration changes
- Follow the required handover procedures for shift changes to ensure service continuity
- Report and escalate incidents where necessary
- Ensure the efficient and comprehensive resolutions of incidents and requests
- Proactively identify opportunities for work optimisation

04/2019 - 04/2020

Grad Intern Configuration Analyst, Dimension Data, Port Elizabeth in South Africa Responsibilities:

- Work directly with users and customers to identify needs and resolve software configuration problems
- Monitor and troubleshoot common and daily tasks and events as well as changes
- Supervise the installation and configuration of computer hardware and software that have been customized to suit the organization's requirements
- Conduct ongoing tests on stored and retrieved data to see that the system functions as expected
- Prepare data and information for making regular report data analysis
- Perform data analysis for complex data and files

Education

2014 - 2016

NDip Information Technology: Communication Networks, Nelson Mandela University 2020 - 2021

Btech Information Technology: Communication Networks, Nelson Mandela University

Certifications

Cisco Certified Network Associate Routing and Switching
Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician
CompTIA A+
CompTIA Network+
Microsoft Certified: Azure Fundamentals
ITIL v4 Foundation
CompTIA IT Operations Specialist – CIOS Stackable Certification
AWS Cloud